Guide to The Karl and Erna Kordesch Papers 1906-2011
Special Collections Archives Research Center, The Valley Library
- Biographical Materials and Photographs, 1906-2010; undated; 3; 10 boxes
  - Photographs, 1900s-2000s; undated; 5; 4 boxes
    - Photographs, 1900s-2000s; undated (Box 3.007)
      - Photographs of Karl and Erna Kordesch, 1970s (Folder 7.12)
      - Photographs of Karl and Erna Kordesch, 1980s (Folder 7.13)
      - Photographs of Karl and Erna Kordesch, 1990s (Folder 7.14)
      - Photographs of Karl and Erna Kordesch, 2000s (Folder 7.15)
      - Photographs of the Kordesch family, 1940s (Folder 7.16)
      - Photographs of the Kordesch family, 1950s (Folder 7.17)
      - Photographs of the Kordesch family, 1960s (Folder 7.18)
      - Photographs of the Kordesch family, 1970s (Folder 7.19)
      - Photographs of the Kordesch family, 1990s (Folder 7.20)
      - Photographs of the Kordesch family, 2000s (Folder 7.21)
      - Photographs of the Bӧhm/Colnago family, 1900s (Folder 7.22)
      - Photographs of the Bӧhm/Colnago family, 1910s (Folder 7.23)
      - Photographs of the Bӧhm/Colnago family, 1920s (Folder 7.24)
      - Photographs of the Bӧhm/Colnago family, 1930s (Folder 7.25)
      - Photographs of the Bӧhm/Colnago family, 1940s (Folder 7.26)
      - Photographs of the Bӧhm/Colnago family, 2000s (Folder 7.27)
      - Photographs of the Marko family, undated (Folder 7.28)
      - Assorted photographs, 1910s (Folder 7.29)
      - Assorted photographs, 1920s (Folder 7.30)
      - Assorted photographs, 1930s (Folder 7.31)
      - Assorted photographs, 1940s (Folder 7.32)
      - Assorted photographs, 1950s (Folder 7.33)
      - Assorted photographs, 1960s (Folder 7.34)
      - Assorted photographs, 1980s (Folder 7.35)
      - Assorted photographs, 1990s (Folder 7.36)
      - Assorted photographs, 2000s (Folder 7.37)
    - Photo Albums, 1926-2002 (Box 3.008)
      - Bӧhm family photo album, 1926-1932 (Folder 8.1)
      - Kordesch Engagement Book/Photo Album, 1940s (Folder 8.2)
      - Karl Kordesch's 80th birthday celebration, 2002 (Folder 8.3)
    - Photo Albums, 1977 (Box 3.009)
      - Union Carbide retirement celebration, 1977 (Folder 9.1)
    - Assorted Slides and Photographic Negatives, undated (Box 3.010)
- Electronic Records, 4; 1 box; 11 gigabytes
  Preservation copies of electronic records including research data, publications, photographs, personal records, video interviews, and correspondence and physical storage media including flash memory drives, Secure Digital memory cards, compact discs, and floppy disks containing original Kordesch documents. Preservation copies of all electronic records are available onsite for researcher use. Additional processing is forthcoming.
  - Digital Media Storage Devices, undated; 1; 1 box
    Storage devices containing Kordesch electronic records in original state and order.
    - Digital Media Storage Devices (Box 4.001)
      - 11 USB flash drives (assorted capacity), undated (Folder 1.1)
      - 2 Secure Digital memory cards, undated (Folder 1.2)
      - 9 compact discs, undated (Folder 1.3)
      - 1 3.5-inch floppy disk, undated (Folder 1.4)
- Books, 1943-2005; 5; 19 volumes
  Volumes from Karl Kordesch's personal library.
  - Blomen, Leo, ed. Fuel Cell 2000 Proceedings. Switzerland: European Fuel Cell Forum, 2000.
  - Bockris, John O'M., T. Nejat Veziroğlu and Debbie Smith. Solar Hydrogen Energy: The Power to Save the Earth. London: Macdonald Co., 1991.
  - D'Ans, Jean and Ellen Lax, eds. Taschenbuch für Chemiker und Physiker. Berlin: Springer/Verlag, 1943.
  - Fuel Cell Seminar Organizing Committee. 1998 Fuel Cell Seminar Abstracts. 1996.
  - Fuel Cell Seminar Organizing Committee. October 2000 Fuel Cell Seminar Abstracts. 2000. 1996.
  - Fuel Cell Seminar Organizing Committee. November 2003 Fuel Cell Seminar Abstracts. 2003. 1996.
  - Fuel Cell Seminar Organizing Committee. 2005 Fuel Cell Seminar Abstracts. 2005. 1996.
  - Gutmann, G. Electrochemical Engineering: Elekotrochemische Raktoren, Energiespeicher und Energiewandler.. Germany: Universitätsverlag Ulm GmbH, 1996.
  - Himy, Albert Silver-Zinc Battery: Phenomena, Design Principles, Manufacturing and Various Topics. College Park, MD: University Press, 2003.
  - Journal of Power Sources. Vol. 51, Nos. 1-2. eds. Dyer, C. K., D. A. J. Rand, and P.T. Moseley, 1994.
  - Kordesch, Karl. "The Electric Automobile". Alternative Energy Sources for the Steel Industry: Proceedings of the Sixth C. C. Furnas Memorial Conference. ed. Julian Szekely. New York: Marcel Dekker, 1977.
  - Kordesch, Karl and Günter Simader. Fuel Cells and Their Applications. Weinheim, Germany: VCH, 1996.
  - Kordesch, Karl. Brennstoffbatterien. Wien, Austria: Springer-Verlag, 1984.
  - Kratzl, Karl. Die Kritik der Unreinen Vernunft: Eine Kantige Angelegenheit in 200 Karikaturen und Anekdoten. Wien, Austria: A. Riegelnik, 1995.
  - National Fuel Cell Coordinating Group. 1982 National Fuel Cell Seminar Abstracts. 1982.
  - Rand, D. A. J., R. Woods, R. M. Dell. Batteries for Electric Vehicles. Somerset, England: Research Studies Press Ltd., 1998.
  - Schwabe, Ina, ed. Batterien und Ladekonzepte. Munich, Germany: Design Elektronik, 1997.
  - Trumbore, Forrest A. Dennis R. Turner. The Electrochemical Society: 1902-2002: A Centennial History. Pennington, NJ: ECS, 2002.
  - Westbrook, Michael H. The Electric Car: Development and future of battery, hybrid and fuel-cell cars. London: IET, 2001.